Shahrukh Tramboo

71C Alamdar colony, Rawalpora, Srinagar, J&K (+91)9103018920 tramboos123@gmail.com

Dedicated Engineer with 3 years and 6 months of experience in both frontend and backend software development & problem solving skills to find the best possible solutions. Passionate about cybersecurity, linux development and new technologies to provide simple & reliable solutions

Technical Skills

- Languages: Java, Javascript, SQL, PHP, HTML5, CSS3
- Frameworks, Libraries & DBMS: Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Jhipster, Angular, Ngrx, D3.js, Mysql, Laravel, Bootstrap, JQuery
- Testing Frameworks: Junit 5, Mockito, Karma, Jasmine, Jest, testing-library
- Platforms: JBOSS, Tomcat, Apache
- Tools: Intellij idea, Eclipse, Git, JIRA, Jenkins, Maven, Jasper reports, Docker, Keycloak (SSO)
- Operating systems: Windows, Ubuntu, Kali Linux

Soft Skills

- Verbal and written communication
- Problem solving
- Quick learner
- Self-motivated and can work with minimal supervision
- Pro-active and enthusiastic

Experience

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

$\textbf{Senior Software Engineer } I \mid \texttt{Ascent Risk \& Resilience} \neq \texttt{Gurugram, Haryana}$

This is a product based company, which has three products (**AutoBCM**, **AutoEscrow** and **AutoRecon**). I have worked on AutoBCM, which is a resilience based application which lets us manage operations and assess risks. I have also worked on AutoRecon, which is an end-to-end automated reconciliation software solution for financial control.

I am full stack developer here, my main tech is Spring boot, Angular, Sql.

The framework we use is Jhipster.

JULY 2021 - MARCH 2022

${\bf Software\ Developer\ -\ Freelance\ |\ Pragtex\ GMBH\ /\ Friedrichshafen,\ Germany}$

My role was to develop both frontend and backend applications for our client which was ZF Friedrichshafen - a manufacturing company based in Germany. We used Keycloak as Single Sign On for all our applications. All applications were dockerised. Tech stack included Angular and Java (Spring Boot). We developed many applications such as:

- **Fleet-configurator**: This was based on fleets (a group of vehicles). We managed the location of vehicles and their drivers and regularly updating the location.
- **Vehicle Calendar**: In this project we assigned jobs to vehicle drivers and regularly kept track of their movements.
- **Service-space**: In this project the main objective was to enhance self-driving cars, by automating their cameras, and checking the health of cars, and regularly updating their location.

SEPT 2019 - MAY 2021

Associate - IT | Art housing finance ltd / Gurugram, Haryana

My role was developing the new projects and give support to existing projects and adding features to it along with deployment.

- **Expense Art Portal**: This project included everything related to day to day expenses in the company, we built the reports for the expenses using software like Jasper reports, there were escalation matrix involved and the tech stack used was php and jQuery library along with bootstrap.
- Audit Portal: This project digitized the internal and external audit process of the company. We developed an application which saved the data raised from all the queries associated with the audit process, and a good feature of the software was the dashboard involving designing of charts using the javascript framework D3.js. The tech stack also included Java(Spring MVC) and jQuery along with bootstrap.
- IT report Portal: This project was based on the parcel delivery for IT products, repairment, and all other day to day requirements. The tech stack included Angular, and Java(Spring Boot).

JULY 2019 - SEP 2019

Intern | Art housing finance ltd / Gurugram, Haryana

In this role, my purpose was to familiarize myself with current ongoing in-house projects and give support to team for java based projects.

Education

JULY 2014 - JUN 2019

Bachelor of Engineering / University of Kashmir, Jammu & Kashmir, India SSM College of engineering, passed with 66.76%

FEB 2012 - MAR 2014

Higher Secondary School / New Convent Hr. sec school, Jammu & Kashmir, India Jammu and Kashmir board of school education, passed 12th with 62%

JUNE 2000 - DEC 2011

Primary School / Tiny Harts School, Jammu & Kashmir, India Jammu and Kashmir board of school education, passed 10th with 92%

Training

FEB 2019 - SEPT 2019

Java training / Ducat, Noida, India

I learned the core basics of Java, and spring framework here, along with SQL and noSQL databases.

MAR 2019 - MAY 2019

Redhat linux training/ Ducat, Noida, India

I learned the basics of linux here, along with networking concepts also everything there is regarding redhat linux.

ONLINE TRAININGS

- Microservices with Spring boot and Cloud / Udemy
- Testing Java with Junit 5 & Mockito / Udemy
- Angular with Test Driven Development / Udemy
- Offensive pentesting learning path / TryHackMe
- CompTIA pentest+ learning path / TryHackMe
- Python & Ethical hacking / Udemy
- Wordpress developer / Udemy
- NgRx (with NgRx Data) / Udemy

Activities

Football • Basketball • Art • Singing

Personal Information

• Mobile: +919103018920

• Github: https://github.com/Shahtr1

• Twitter: https://twitter.com/CLAYster404

• LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shahrukh-tramboo/